

Vinicius Renan de Carvalho

LINKEDIN: @VINIXNAN

HTTPS://VINIXNAN.GITHUB.IO/

HTTPS://WWW.LINKEDIN.COM/IN/VINIXNAN/

VINICIUSRENAN.CARVALHO@GMAIL.COM

+44 07796000134

ABOUT ME

My I.T. career started with Web Development, more precisely with PHP and Java EE development, coding web services and systems. After four years of experience, I decided to full-time study Artificial Intelligence and its applications as a graduate student. In this field, I'd been studying Evolutionary Computation and Machine Learning in the past four years, applying A.I. to real-world problems. Currently, I have been studying the combination of multi-agent, evolutionary computation, and machine learning techniques in order to produce autonomous algorithms. Also, I have been studying Deep Leaning and other machine learning techniques.

QUALIFICATIONS

2016 - 2020 University of São Paulo (USP)

PhD in Computer Engineering, Artificial Intelligence

2014 - 2015

Federal University of Parana (UFPR)

Master degree in Computer Science, Search Based Software Engineering

2009 - 2012 University Western Sao Paulo (Unoeste) Bachelor degree in Information Systems

WORK EXPERIENCE

Doctoral Fellow – 2018 to Present University of Nottingham – Nottingham, UK

Doing part of my Ph.D. in ASAP group having Ender Ozcan as advisor

Doctoral Fellow – 2016 to Present University of São Paulo – São Paulo, Brazil

My research entitled "Multi-Agent Election Based Hyper-Heuristic" focus on online selecting the most suitable Multi-Objective Evolutionary Algorithms (MOEA) in order to find solutions for discrete problems (such as TSP) and continuous (such as vehicle crashworthiness). This research employs Social Choice techniques and considers MOEAs as agents.

Masters Fellow – 07/2014 to 12/2015 Federal University of Parana – Curitiba, Brazil

During my master degree I studied several topics of Artificial Intelligence (AI) and Software Engineering (SE). The following IA subjects were studied: Mono-objective algorithms: Genetic Algorithm (GA), Particle Swarm Optimization (PSO), Ant Colony Optimization (ACO) and Simulated Annealing (SA); Multi-objective algorithms: NSGA -II, SPEA2, MOEA/D and IBEA; Hyper-heuristics: Choice Function, Multi Armed Bandit and FRRMAB;

AWARDS

2012 Brazilian Computer Society Outstanding Student **2012** Best of Information Systems graduates

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Proficient: Java, PHP, SQL, XML, REST, Git, Unit test, UML, Continuous Integration, Evolutionary Computation and Machine Learning.

Intermediate: C, Python.

Familiar with: Deep Leaning, Natural Language

Processing

ADDITIONAL ACADEMIC AND RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Conference Subreviewer:

- AIH Joint Workshop on Artificial Intelligence for Health (2018)
- GCAI: Global Conference on Artificial Intelligence (2018)
- BRACIS Brazilian Conference on Intelligent Systems (2016 and 2018)
- PAAMS International Conference on Practical Applications of Agents and MultiAgent Systems (2017)
- ENIAC Encontro Nacional de Inteligencia Artificial e Computacional (2016)

Teaching Assistant:

University of Sao Paulo

Assignment preparation and correction in the subject Introduction to Artificial Intelligence

Federal University of Parana

Assignment preparation and correction in the subjects: Introduction to scientific method {Software Engineering Topics 2009 – 2010

Student monitor:

University of Western Sao Paulo (Unoeste)

Helping other students as subject monitor in the following subjects: Logic, Algorithms and Programming Techniques I and II, Computer lab II, Data structure I, Programming languages I.

Web Developer – 02/2014 to 07/2014 RevendaMais – Curitiba, Brazil

Second level support for a car sales system (PHP + Codelgniter). Webservices Developer (SOAP/REST/XML) for several integrations as MercadoLivre, WebMotors, Icarros.

Web Developer – 09/2011 to 02/2014 Magote – São Paulo, Brazil

I worked in coding and maintenance in PHP systems using the framework Codelgniter, also in Java systems using JSF framework and Hibernate. I also worked in the configuration and maintenance of Linux servers (Ubuntu Server with Apache and Glassfish) and second level support.

Junior Web Developer – 04/2011 to 09/2011

WebLibre – São Paulo, Brazil

I was involved in the development of the payment gateway Librepag (coded in PHP)